《行尸走肉》前情提要
Previously on AMC's The Walking Dead...
- 动他可能会情况恶化  - 那怎么做能让他好转呢?
- Moving him could make him worse.  - What will make him better?
让他醒过来
Waking up.
我以为你很弱 但你向我证明了我是错的
I thought you were weak. You've proved me wrong.
这是药柜的钥匙
This is to the drug locker.
你要救那个女人
You are gonna save that woman's life.
这个丹只是想维持现在的状态 对吧?
This Dawn, she's just trying to keep it together, right?
如果我们能活捉几个警察
If we get a couple of her cops alive,
就能公平交易 他们的人换我们的
we do an even trade. Theirs for ours.
大家都能安然回家
Everybody goes home.
我了解这个女人 让我帮你们
I know this woman. Let me help you.
站住
Stop.
立刻站住
Stop right now.
站住
Stop.
最后一遍
I won't ask again.
该死
Oh, shit.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
你个混蛋 帮帮我
You son of a bitch. Help me.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
帮帮我
Help me.
你个... 疯子
You crazy... you crazy son of a bitch.
我觉得... 你撞伤了我的后背
I think you... I think you broke my back.
又不是非得撞你的
Didn't have to be like this.
你得站住
You just had to stop.
我不能停 我不了解你
I couldn't. I don't know you.
但我觉得... 我现在了解了
But I think... I think I'm getting the idea.
你得听话站住
You just had to stop.
带我回去
Take me back.
带我回医院
Take me back to the hospital.
我是为了你朋友那么做的
I did it for your friend.
你逃了 就没机会了
Not after this, no.
没后悔药 鲍勃
Can't go back, Bob.
我本来想解决好这事的
I was gonna iron it over.
就拿她来开刀
She's under it.
你出来太久了
And you've been out here too long.
你会死的 你们都会...
You'll die. You'll all...
闭嘴
Shut up.
《行尸走肉》
求求你们!
Please!
让我进去!
Let me in!
求求你们! 让我进去!
Please! Let me in!
他们逼近了!
They're close!
救命! 他们来了!
Help! They're coming!
请别把我一个人留在外面!
Please don't leave me out here!
求求你们!
Please!
请别把我留在外面!
Don't leave me out here!
卡尔! 米琼恩! 救命!
Carl! Michonne!
我必须得看看! 我现在明白了!
I had to see it! I know now!
让我带着罪孽活下去!
Let me live with it!
神啊 救救我
Oh, God, please.
- 等等  - 救命!
- Wait.  - Help!
让我进去! 天啊 求求你们!
Let me in! Oh, God, please!
救我! 救命!
Help me! Help!
卡尔! 米琼恩! 救命!
Carl! Michonne!
后退
Get back.
求求你们! 救命!
Please! Help!
救命!
Help!
救救我!
Help me!
天啊 求求你们!
Oh, God, please!
让我进去! 让我进去!
Let me in! Let me in!
救救我!
Help me!
求求你们 让我进去!
Please, let me in!
- 求求你们!  - 快点!
- Please!  - Come on!
救命!
Help!
后退
Get back.
去教区长的房间
The rectory, come on.
我就是这么出去的 从下面爬出去
That's how I got out. Crawl under to the back.
快走 带上小孩走
Just go. Take the little one and go.
嘿 嘿 在外面等我
Hey, hey. You wait for me.
一切都值得
It's worth it.
我会等你走了再松手
I'm not going anywhere until you're gone.
- 来吧  - 我没法跑了
- Come on.  - I can't run anymore.
我们不跑
We're not running.
他不肯站住
He wouldn't stop.
那得改计划了?
This change things?
必须得改
It has to.
也许不用
Maybe not.
她说计划没法成功 觉得能成功的家伙死了
She said the plan won't work. The guy who did is dead.
也许我们该重新考虑一下
Maybe we gotta rethink this.
他们也说了 管事的警察不喜欢他
They also said the cop in charge didn't have any love for him.
也许你帮了她个忙
Maybe you did her a favor.
我不知道他们会不会耍花样
I don't know if they'll play ball.
问问就知道了
Let's find out.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
他被行尸袭击了
He was attacked by rotters.
我们看着他死的
Saw it go down.
你撒谎真厉害
You're a damn good liar.
我们现在命悬一线
We're hanging by a thread here.
他是被行尸袭击了 就是这样
He was attacked by rotters. That's the story.
你说过 交易是个坏主意
You said the trade was a bad idea.
什么变了?
What changed?
拉姆森原本是我们的希望
Lamson was our shot.
现在要不就帮你们 要不你们就杀进去 对吧?
So it's this or you go in guns blazing, right?
你不想让我们杀进去
You don't want that.
如果你敢胡说八道
If this is some bullshit you're spinning
- 计划失败...  - 我知道
- and things go south...  - I know.
我知道哪些是好警察
I know the good ones from the bad.
让我们帮你
Let us help you.
那你呢?
What about you?
你想活吗? 有多想?
You wanna live? How much?
丹害怕让我们觉得她很脆弱
Dawn's afraid she'll look weak in front of us.
觉得这会让我们反抗她
Thinks it'll tip things against her.
的确如此
Hell, it will.
如果她觉得你们杀了我们的人
She'll see this trade as a rip-off
就会认为这个交易是在敲诈
if she thinks you took out one of our guys.
所以幸好拉姆森是被行尸杀掉的
So it's a good thing Lamson got aced by rotters.
谢帕德 还有拉姆森 你们在哪儿?
Shepherd, Lamson, what's your 20?
汇报之前的枪声是怎么回事 听到吗?
I need status on that gunfire. Do you copy?
利卡里 听到吗?
Licari, do you copy?
有人听到吗?
Does anybody copy?
该死
Damn it.
出问题了?
Something wrong?
他们有时候就是不回话
They don't always radio back
我都快疯了
and it drives me crazy.
等等 别 别 Beth 别放那儿
Wait, no, no, no. Beth, no, not there.
放警徽旁边
Up by the badges.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是汉森队长吗?
Is this Captain Hanson?
有人告诉过你他的事情吗?
Did someone say something about him to you?
我只听说以前是他管事
Just that he used to be in charge.
你会听到他的故事
Well, you'll hear stories about him.
我的故事
About me.
我都做了些什么
About what I did.
他是我的良师
He was my mentor.
益友
My friend.
我很想他
I miss him.
传闻里面没包括这些
That's the part the stories leave out.
他怎么了?
What happened to him?
每次外出行动
They risk their lives
他们都冒着生命危险
every time they go out there.
冒险总得有意义 有结果
It has to be worth it. It has to matter.
但是他忽视了这一点
He lost sight of that.
所以他也失去了人心
So he lost them.
贝斯 做我这活的人并不需要他人的爱戴...
Beth, in this job you don't need their love...
但是一定得赢得他们的尊重
but you have to have their respect.
否则 总有一天
Otherwise, the day is gonna come
在你需要的时候 你却找不到后盾
when you need backup and you don't have it.
接下来呢?
And what comes next?
大家都得完蛋
Everybody goes down.
汉森迷失了自我
Hanson lost his way.
就是这样
That's what happened.
你去哪了?
Where did you go?
学校
The school.
我得亲眼看看
I had to see.
我得弄清楚
I had to know.
我们往哪跑?
Where do we go?
- 你没事吧?  - 没事
- You okay?  - Yeah.
你们回来了
You're back.
尤金说谎了
Eugene lied.
他没法挽救这一切
He can't stop it.
华盛顿没有终结一切的办法
Washington isn't the end.
大家都在哪?
Where is everybody?
贝斯还活着 她在亚特兰大的一个医院里
Beth's alive. She's in a hospital in Atlanta.
有人带走了她 其他人都去救她了
Some people have her, but the others went to get her back.
知道是哪个医院吗?
Do we know which one?
格雷迪纪念医院
Grady Memorial.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们快点走吧 去救你的妹妹
Let's blow this joint, go save your sister.
不 帕西 告诉我 你还要我说得清楚点吗?
No, Percy, tell me. Should I use smaller words?
把我袖子上破洞补好 这指令太难吗?
Is the directive fix the hole in my sleeve too complicated for you?
- 抱歉 我忘记了  - 好啊 那就听好了
- I'm sorry. I forgot.  - Well, here's an idea.
不许忘记
Don't forget.
你怎么样?
What about you?
- 针线活好不好?  - 我需要她
- You any good with needle and thread?  - I need her.
不好意思 我们有好多活要干 走吧 Beth
Sorry, we have a lot of work to do. Come on, Beth.
帕西会没事的
Percy's going to be okay.
什么都不会没事的
Nothing's okay.
你要跳下去吗?
Are you going to jump?
我就想一个人静静
I wanted to be alone.
正好你把电梯钥匙留在了原处
You left your elevator key where it was.
我知道你哪也不会去
Well, I know you're not going anywhere.
你也是
Neither are you.
你...
You...
你总是说服自己为了等这场噩梦过去
you keep telling yourself you have to do whatever it takes
要不计代价
just until this is all over.
但不可能结束的
But it isn't over.
就是这样
This is it.
一切结束之前 你不会变 这地方也不会变
This is who you are and what this place is until the end.
这地方救了你的命
This place saved you.
我救了你的命
I saved you.
两次
Twice.
其他人不知道你做了什么
The others don't know what you did.
他们以为琼是要背叛我
They think Joan was trying to get back at me
以为戈尔曼和杰弗里斯当了替死鬼
and that Gorman and Jeffries were in the wrong place at the wrong time.
- 事情就是这样的  - 胡说
- That's what happened.  - Bullshit.
我看到碎罐子了
I saw the smashed jar.
我关了办公室 在别人发现前处理掉了
I closed up my office and I fixed it before it could be a problem.
你杀了个警察
You're a cop killer.
- 我不会杀人的  - 但是你杀了
- I would never kill somebody.  - But you did.
你知不知道 别人要是发现了会怎么样?
What do you think would happen if the others found out?
是我保护了你
I protected you.
而且我们救了那个病人
And we helped that patient.
我没必要那么做 但是我想要
I didn't have to, I wanted to.
但是这里的事都要按规矩来
But there's a way things have to happen here.
你不明白吗?
Don't you get that?
你想干什么?
What are you gonna do?
不 丹 是你想干什么?
No, Dawn, what are you gonna do?
先从她开始说
Starting with her.
她是我的人 这是我的事
She's my ward. It's my call.
好吧 但是这里的人得知道他们在为谁干活
Fine, but your people deserve to know who they're working for.
是你去告诉他们 还是我来?
So, you gonna tell them or am I?
你别威胁我
You don't get to threaten me.
这不是威胁
That's not a threat.
但这都是事实 你的状况糟透了
But these are the facts. You look like shit.
大家都在议论你 觉得你要崩溃了
The guys are talking. They think you're cracking.
又要变成汉森那时一样了
This is Hanson all over again.
是时候改变了
It's time to make a change.
停下 奥唐纳
O'Donnell.
你错了
You're wrong.
我一点都不像汉森
I'm nothing like Hanson.
是我杀了他 你记得吗?
I was the one who killed him, remember that?
我是唯一一个能那么做的人
I was the only one who could go through with it.
放下你的武器 丹
Lower your weapon, Dawn.
不然我就要喊了
All I have to do is shout.
那我会说是你来找我麻烦
All I have to do is say you came at me.
贝斯 到安全的地方去
Beth, get out of the way.
你不会开枪的
You're not gonna do this.
是你逼我的
You're not giving me a choice.
过来
Go.
我们当年是同期的新人
We were rookies together.
你也认识我的妻子
You knew my wife.
我孩子刚出生的时候
You were here in this hospital
你也在这个医院 我们在停车场一起抽过烟
having cigars with me in the parking lot when my kid was born.
闭嘴
Don't.
那个你已经不在了
That guy is gone.
我们本该保护大家的
We're supposed to protect people.
帮助他们
To help them.
可是 看看你
But look at you.
你竟然殴打老人
You're beating the old man.
那个可怜姑娘被强奸的时候
You're laughing with your buddies
你竟然和兄弟一起大笑
about that poor girl getting raped.
- 那才是现在的你  - 那你又是什么东西?
- That's who you are now.  - So who the hell are you?
不会放纵这一切发生的人
Somebody who's not gonna let it happen anymore.
这都不是关键
That's not what this is about.
关键是要紧抓住仅有的东西不放
It's about holding on to what you have.
我还剩下什么?
What the hell do I have?
你已经不是你了
This isn't you.
汉森死掉之后 你就变了
After Hanson, you changed.
你觉得你比我们强?!
You think you're better than us?!
管好你自己的事 婊子!
Stay in your lane, bitch!
贝斯 推下去!
Beth!
谢谢
Thank you.
哭出来没事的
It's okay to cry.
我不会再哭了
I don't cry anymore.
我会
I do.
只是不让别人看到罢了
I just don't let them see it.
这是我自己的东西
It's from my own stash.
不用你干活来换
There's no strings.
我知道你为什么替我隐瞒
I know now why you covered for me.
你不是在保护我
You weren't protecting me.
你是在保护你自己
You were protecting yourself.
是吗?
Is that so?
不管是戈尔曼 杰弗里斯 还是奥唐纳
Gorman, Jeffries, O'Donnell...
他们对你来说是威胁
they were problems for you.
但现在不是了
And now they're not.
而你还不用亲自动手
And you didn't have to do the dirty work.
这就是这里的处事方式
That's how things get done here.
人人都为了自己想要的东西而互相利用
Everyone uses people to get what they want.
你自己就不用记得那些被杀掉的人
You're not the ones who have to remember.
爱德华和特雷维特的事也是这样吗?
Is that what happened with Edwards and Trevitt?
他利用了你?
He used you?
我会出去的
I'm gonna get out.
就像诺亚一样
Just like Noah.
他会回来的
He'll be back.
- 他要回家了  - 他们总会回来的
- He's going home.  - They always come back.
他们根本走不远 因为他们没办法走远
They don't ever get far because they can't.
但真正的原因是...
But really...
他们不想离开
they don't want to.
他要回家了
He's going home.
我年轻时跟你一样
I was like you when I was younger.
谁的话也听不进去
Nobody could tell me anything.
我现在不傻了
I'm not stupid.
你认识她
You know her.
不管以何种方式 你们最终都来了这里
And somehow you both wound up here.
也许这是有所暗示的
Maybe that means something.
贝斯 你可以成为这里的一份子
Beth, you can be a part of this thing.
你们俩都是
Both of you.
这很重要
This is important.
可能是你这辈子做的最重要的事
Maybe the most important thing you do in your life.
而你刚刚在那里做的...
And what you did back there...
戈尔曼和奥唐纳害人不浅
Gorman and O'Donnell hurt people.
他们的死对这个世界没有任何损失
The world didn't lose anything when they died.
你刚刚那话也说错了
And you're wrong about what happened.
我没有利用你
I didn't use you.
我会记得死去的人
And I will remember.
你在自责
You're beating yourself up.
不要这样
Don't.
我当时犯傻了
I was stupid.
在教堂
At the church,
你杀的那个人
that guy you killed,
他叫马丁
his name was Martin.
我们曾经抓到他了
We had him.
我和卡罗尔
Me and Carol.
还在终点站的时候
Back by Terminus.
后来 她跟着你们走了
Then she went in after you all
当时就只剩我和他
and it was just me and him.
我曾说我杀死他了
I said I killed him.
我本可以那么做的
I could have done it,
也许我也应该那么做 但是...
maybe I should have done it, but...
我没有
I didn't.
我一直在想这件事
I keep thinking abt it.
我记得我们还是孩子的时候
I remember when we were kids
你常常跟着我到处跑
and you used to follow me around,
模仿我做的每件小事
copying every little thing I did.
我们所经历的事
What happened to both of us,
也许是因为我们还是一样
maybe it's because we're still the same.
还是从前的样子
Just like we were back then.
也许这是好事
And maybe that's good.
你的确没变
You're still the same.
这是好事
And that is good.
但我觉得我做不到
I don't think I can be.
再也回不去了
Not anymore.
回不去了
他们正在往对我们有利的位置开
They're headed towards the vantage point.
好的
Okay.
收到
Copy that.
弗朗哥警官 麦金利警官
Officer Franco. Officer McGinley.
我是瑞克 格兰姆斯
I'm Rick Grimes.
我曾是国王县治安局的副警长
I was a deputy in the King County Sheriff's Department.
我来是想做个交易
I'm here to make a proposal.
把你的枪放在地上
Lay your weapon on the ground.
好的
All right.
什么交易?
What's your proposal?
你们手里有我的两个人 我有你们的两个人
You have two of my people, I have two of yours.
我们想做个交换
We want to make an exchange.
然后我们就各走各的路 没有人会受伤
Then we'll be on our way. No one gets hurt.
- 谁?  - 谢帕德警官
- Who?  - Officers Shepherd
和利卡里警官 换贝斯和卡罗尔
and Licari for Beth and Carol.
你们昨天用车撞了个女人
You picked up a woman yesterday
后来还把她带走了
after your people hit her with a car.
诺亚 他跟你在一起吗? 是他告诉你的?
Noah, he's with you? That's how you know?
是的
Yes, he is.
拉姆森警官呢?
What about Officer Lamson?
我们找到他的时候 他已经被行尸弄死了
He was attacked by the dead before we got to him.
你的人在哪儿?
Where are your people?
他们离得很近
They're close.
用对讲机跟你们中尉报告 我会等着
Radio your lieutenant. I'll wait.
把枪收进枪套里
Holster your weapons.
你也是
You, too.
他们没有受伤
They haven't been harmed.
拉姆森在哪儿?
Where's Lamson?
行尸袭击了他
Rotters got him.
我们看到他死了
We saw it go down.
哦
Oh.
真遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
他是个好人
He was one of the good guys.
一个换一个
One of yours for one of mine.
好的
All right.
走
Move.
很高兴我们把事情解决了
Glad we could work things out.
是啊
Yeah.
现在我只要Noah
Now I just need Noah.
然后你们就可以离开了
And then you can leave.
交易里可没这条
That wasn't part of the deal.
诺亚是我的人
Noah was my ward.
贝斯接替了他的位置 但她又离开了 所以我要他回来
Beth took his place and I'm losing her, so I need him back.
- 长官 这不...  - Shepherd!
- Ma'am, please, it's not...  - Shepherd!
我的警官们冒着生命危险出去找他
My officers put their lives on the line to find him.
他们中死了一个
One of them died.
不 他不会留下
No, he ain't staying.
他是我的人 你们无权带走他
He's one of mine. You have no claim on him.
这孩子想回家 所以你无权留下他
The boy wants to go home, so you have no claim on him.
这样我们就做不成交易了
Well, then we don't have a deal.
交易已经结束了
The deal is done.
- 没关系  - 不 不行
- It's okay.  - No. No.
我要留下
I got to do it.
不可以
It's not okay.
就这么定了
It's settled.
等等!
Wait!
没关系
It's okay.
我知道你会回来的
I knew you'd be back.
我现在明白了
I get it now.
不! 别开枪!
No! Hold your fire!
结束了
It's over.
她已经死了
It was just about her.
放下
Stand down.
你们可以留下
You can stay.
我们在这里活得很好
We're surviving here.
比外面好
It's better than out there.
不
No.
我还要把想走的人一起带走
And I'm taking anyone back there who wants to leave.
如果想跟我们一起走的...
If you want to come with us...
现在就站出来
just step forward now.
《行尸走肉》将于二月回归
AMC's The Walking Dead returns with new episodes this February.
我们离那里有几百英里
We are hundreds miles away.
要有地方能让我们安全留下呢?
What if some place we can be safe?
是个机会
It's a chance.
总好过留在外面
Instead of just being out here.
总好过白手起家
Instead of just making it.
我们没事
We're okay.
因为这才是我们的生存之道
Because this is how we survive.
《行尸走肉》将于二月回归
The Walking Dead returns with new episodes this February.
AMC台呈献
Only on AMC.
(抱歉 我太混蛋了 一定要来华盛顿 新世界需要瑞克 格兰姆斯)